Guide to the East Side House Records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series V: Programs and Services
  - New York City Housing Authority Cash Expenditures, 1981-83 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - New York City Housing Authority Cash Expenditures, 1986-88 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - New York City Housing Authority Cash Expenditures, 1989-91 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - New York City Housing Authority Correspondence, 1966-91 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - New York City Housing Authority Narrative Reports, 1982 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - New York City Housing Authority Narrative Reports, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - New York City Housing Authority Narrative Reports, 1986 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - New York City Housing Authority Narrative Reports, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - New York City Housing Authority Narrative Reports, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - New York City Housing Authority Narrative Reports, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - New York City Housing Authority Narrative Reports, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - New York City Housing Authority Narrative Reports, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - New York City Housing Authority Statistical Reports, 1982 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - New York City Housing Authority Statistical Reports, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - New York City Housing Authority Statistical Reports, 1986 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - New York City Housing Authority Statistical Reports, 1987 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - New York City Housing Authority Statistical Reports, 1988 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - New York City Housing Authority Statistical Reports, 1989 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - New York City Housing Authority Statistical Reports, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - New York City Housing Authority Statistical Reports, 1991 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - New York State Adolescent Vocational Exploration Program, 1989-90 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - New York State. Department of Social Services Mill Brook Children and Family Service Project, 1989-90 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - New York State. Department of Social Services Enrichment and Parent School Project, 1988-91 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - New York State. Department of Social Services Weekend Senior Citizen Self Help Project, 1989-90 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - New York State. Department of Social Services Youth in Service to Seniors, 1988-89 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Patterson Community Center, 1981-91 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Patterson Senior Center, 1973-1986 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Program Brochures, 1976-86 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - "Program Comments", 1970 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - "Program Comments", 1971 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Program Director-Memos and Correspondence, 1980-92 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Program Enrichment Project, 1981-82 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Program Funding, 1980-91 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Program Overviews, 1981-91 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Program Reports-"Activity for CultureEnrichment and Sports" (ACES), 1977-80 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Program Reports, [nd]-1990 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Program Schedules, 1895-1904 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Program Statistics, [nd]-1990 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Project High Road, 1991 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - South Bronx Golden Glove Project, 1980-83 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - South Bronx Voter Registration Coalition, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Stepney Camp, 1951-66 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Summer Camp, 1907 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Summer Recreation, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Title XX-Senior Citizens Centers, 1980-83 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Tutorial and Parent Involvement Project, 1988 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - VocationalEducational and Employment Project, 1984-91 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Winifred Wheeler Day Nursery Annual Reports, 1901-09 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Winifred Wheeler Day Nursery Annual Reports, 1910-13 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Winifred Wheeler Day Nursery Annual Reports, 1914-16 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Winifred Wheeler Day Nursery Annual Reports, 1917-24 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Winifred Wheeler Day Nursery Brochure, [nd] (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Winifred Wheeler Day Nursery Correspondence, 1982-91 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Winifred Wheeler Day Nursery Evaluations, 1985-89 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Winifred Wheeler Day Nursery Minutes (Bound Volume), 1918-24 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Youth Leadership Training Program, 1981-91 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Youth Programs-Calendar, 1986 (Box 32, Folder 5)
- Series VI: Audio-Visual Materials
  - Subseries VI.1: Photographs
    - Sub-subseries VI.1.1: Prints
      - Anniversaries 90th, 1981 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Anniversaries 95th, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - Anniversaries 96th, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - Anniversaries 100th-Awards Ceremony, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - Anniversaries 100th-Dinner, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - Anniversaries 100th-Parade, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - Annual Meeting, 1992 (Box 33, Folder 7)
      - Arts and Crafts, 1950s-80s (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - Board Meetings, 1980s (Box 33, Folder 9)
      - Board Meeting, 1988 (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - Board Meetings, 1990s (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - Boy's Club, 1950s (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - Bronx Celebrations, 1980s-90s (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - Building Exteriors, 1890s1960s-80s (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - Children-Day Trips, 1970s-80s (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - Children-Groups, 1970s-80s (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - Children-Individual, 1980s (Box 34, Folder 8)
      - Children-Program Activities, 1970s-80s (Box 34, Folder 9)
      - Day Camp, 1970s-90s (Box 34, Folder 10)
      - Demolition, 1980s (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Dinner Events, 1980s (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - Family Day Care, 1970s-80s (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - Fresh Air Fund, 1970s-80s (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - Congressman Garcia Visit, 1988 (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Gymnasium Activities, 1980s (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - Halloween, 1980s (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - Head Start, 1980s-90s (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous, 1970s-90s (Box 35, Folder 9)
        [See also Oversized Materials]
      - National Federation of Settlements, 1908 (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - Neighborhood Scenes, 1970s (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - Parades, 1970s (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - Parades, 1980s (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - Performances, 1950s (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - Performing Arts-"A Walk Through the Century", 1980s (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - Performing Arts-Bands, 1970s-80s (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - Performing Arts-Dance Classes, 1980s (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - Performing Arts-Dance Recitals, 1980s (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Performing Arts-Miscellaneous, 1970s-80s (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Playground Activities, 1970s-80s (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - Program Centers, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 10)
      - Programs-Miscellaneous, 1980s-90s (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Renovations, 1980s (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - William Schnappauf Retirement, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Senior Center-Staff, 1980s (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Senior Citizens-Activities, 1970s-80s (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Senior Citizens-Barbecue, 1980s (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - Senior Citizens-Beauty Contest, 1980s (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Senior Citizens-Christmas/New Year's, 1970s-80s (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - Senior Citizens-Concerts, 1970s-80s (Box 37, Folder 9)
      - Senior Citizens-Concerts, 1970s-80s (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Senior Citizens-Field Trip, 1980s (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Senior Citizens-Flower Garden, 1980s (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Senior Citizens-Groups, 19601970s-80s (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Senior Citizens-Halloween, 1980s (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Senior Citizens-Individual, 1970s-80s (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - Senior Citizens-Variety Show, 1980s (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - Senior Citizens-Wedding, 1987 (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - Sports-Baseball, 1970s (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - Sports-Basketball, 1970s (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - Sports-Boxing, 1970s-80s (Box 38, Folder 11)
      - Sports-Jumping Rope, 1970s (Box 38, Folder 12)
      - Sports-Karate, 1980s (Box 38, Folder 13)
      - Sports-Track and Field, 1970s-80s (Box 38, Folder 14)
      - Sports-Wrestling, 1970s (Box 38, Folder 15)
      - Staff-Groups, 1980s-90s (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Staff-Individuals, 1970s-90s (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Staff Parties, 1980s-90s (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Summer Program-Staff, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - Teens-Group, 1970s-90s (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - Teens-Individuals, 1970s-80s (Box 39, Folder 6)
      - Teens-Program Activities, 1980s-90s (Box 39, Folder 7)
      - Thrift Shop, 1970s (Box 39, Folder 8)
      - Train Trip, 1950s (Box 39, Folder 9)
      - United Neighborhood Houses Retreat, 1994 (Box 39, Folder 10)
      - VocationalEducational and Employment Project, 1980s-90s (Box 39, Folder 11)
      - Winter Antique Show, 1990s (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Youth Leadership, 1970s-90s (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Sub-subseries VI.1.2: Negatives
      - Anniversaries97th, 1988 (Box 40, Folder 3)
      - Anniversaries100th, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 4)
      - Board Meetings, 1980s (Box 40, Folder 5)
      - Demolition, 1980s (Box 40, Folder 6)
      - Halloween, 1980s (Box 40, Folder 7)
      - Parades, 1980s (Box 40, Folder 8)
      - Seniors, 1980s (Box 40, Folder 9)
      - Seniors-Flower Garden, 1980s (Box 40, Folder 10)
      - Staff, 1980s (Box 40, Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous, 1970s-80s (Box 40, Folder 12)
      - Unidentified, 1970s-80s (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Sub-subseries VI.1.3: Transparencies
      - Family Day Care, 1983 (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Head Start, 1983 (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Programs, 1968 (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - Programs, 1969 (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - Senior Citizens, 1983 (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - Special Anniversary Meeting, 1983 (Box 41, Folder 6)
      - Stepney Camp, 1968 (Box 41, Folder 7)
      - Winter Antique Show, 1994 (Box 41, Folder 8)
      - Youth Programs, 1980s (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Subseries VI.2: Video
    - "Bills Retirement Video", 1989 (Box 42, Folder 1)
      [ Commemorates retirement of East Side House Executive Director William Schnappauf with highlights from his career]
    - "Head Start", 1995. (Box 42, Folder 2)
      [ New York 1 News segment on East Side House program]
    - "This Friendly Door", ca.1950. (Box 42, Folder 3)
      [Documents a typical day at East Side House with neighborhood scenes and program activities]
    - "Winter Antique Show", 1995. (Box 42, Folder 4)
      [ABC Eyewitness news segment on East Side House fundraising event]
    - "Service Into the Future", 1987 (Box 43, Folder 1)
      [Centennial Campaign. Clips from "This Friendly Door" videoneighborhood scenes and East Side House program activities from 1980s. Used for fundraising. ]
  - Subseries VI.3: Film
    - Theater Program, 1950s. (Box 43, Folder 2)
      [Short clips from several performances and rehearsals by teens]
- Series VII: Oversized Photographs
  - Miscellaneous-Contact sheet, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 1)